邪恶的银河帝国殒落
前帝国军阀四散在银河各处
密谋让帝国东山再起
羽翼未丰的新共和国开始重整银河系
在无法无天的边境星域
曼达洛人和他的小徒弟古古
四处追捕这些帝国逃犯
我们都同意 帝国统治下的情况较好
I think we can all agree that things were better
under the Empire.
幸好 我还在这里保护你们
Fortunately, I am still here to protect you.
你们的聚落能在我的保护下繁荣发展
Your communities can thrive under my protection.
你们是少数的幸运儿
You are the lucky few.
但我提供的保护所费不赀
But that which I provide is expensive.
如今我得在没有帝国支持下维持运作
And now I must maintain all of it without the
Empire's support
直到银河系明白他们失去什么
until the galaxy realizes what they've lost
并要求我们回归
and demand our return.
帝国万岁
Long live the Empire.
很好
Good.
现在讲坏消息
Now for the bad news.
我要提高你们的保护费
I am raising your tribute.
可是
But
可是阁下 我们处于亏损状态
But, Your Excellency, we are operating at a loss.
贸易路线上充斥海盗与窃贼
The trade routes are plagued with pirates and
thieves,
准备攻击
ready to attack at
你是我说的保护不够吗？
Are you saying that my protection is lacking?
不 阁下
No, Your Excellency.
我是说
I-I am saying that, uh
或许你们都该回自己的区域
Perhaps you should all go back to your townships
专心想出解决方案
and focus on solutions,
而非借口
not excuses.
听起来合理吗？
Does that sound reasonable?
应该是周边警报 我去确认
Sounds like a perimeter alarm. I'll confirm.
-断讯了 -去看看
-I've lost contact. -Go check it.
不必担心 我会去请增援部队
There's nothing to worry about. I'll send for
reinforcements.
我会要求收入预估
I will require a revenue projection
我们需要支援 快点
We need backup. On the double
红色警戒
Code Red.
提供火力掩护
Lay down cover fire.
拿起武器
Take up arms
帝国万岁
Long live the Empire
你在等什么 上来
What are you waiting for? Hop on.
抓好
Hang on.
-逮到他了吗？ -还没 会的
-Did we get him? -Not yet, sir. But we will.
-没打中 他在底下 -他跑不掉的
-We missed him He's under us. -We have him.
发射
Fire.
怎么回事 报告状况
What's going on? Give me a status report.
-歼灭目标了吗？ -断讯了
-Has the target been eliminated? -We've lost
contact.
三号步行机炸毁
Walker Three is gone.
全部出动
Send everybody
了解
Understood.
准备交战
Prepare to engage
准备 武器就绪
Get ready. Weapons up.
弹药满载 出发
Full barrel. Now, let's go.
给我最新状况
Give me a status update.
有看到他吗？ 有发现他的位置吗？
Did you see him? Have you located him?
逮到曼达洛人了吗？
Did you get The Mandalorian?
上面有动静
Something's up there.
他在船顶
He's on the roof
有看见他吗？
Can you see him?
杀了他
Take him out
上去
Get up there.
我们是飞行员
But we're pilots.
快去 快
Go now Do it
是 马上去
Yes, sir. On our way.
上去
Get up there.
设置炸药
Set the charges.
准备撤离 -是
-Prepare for exfil. -Sir.
他想破坏舱门
He's breaching the hatch. He's breaching the hatch
自动驾驶
Autopilot.
我知道 我得击中目标
I know, I know. I need to get the shot.
其实活捉他们比较好
You know, it's better if you bring 'em in alive.
你还好吗？
You okay?
因为 你抓到坏蛋
You see, you catch the bad guy
他们就会供出其他坏蛋在哪
and they tell us where the other bad guys are.
出了一点差错
Things went a little sideways.
《曼达洛人与古古》
祝好运 你需要好运
Good luck. You're gonna need it.
乱来 太乱来了
Messy. Very messy.
在那种情况下我尽力了
It was the best I could do under the circumstances.
问题是我们需要情报
The problem is, we need information.
没有情报 不可能查出帝国的盘算
Without it, we're never gonna get to the bottom of
what the Empire's up to.
给我时间 我会干掉牌上的每个坏蛋
Just give me time, I'll take out every bad guy in
your deck of cards.
这不是为了报复
This isn't about revenge.
而是避免另一场战争
It's about preventing another war
并保护义军奋力守护的一切
and protecting everything the Rebellion fought for.
意思是我这次拿不到钱吗？
Does that mean I'm not getting paid for this one?
你会拿到钱的
You're getting paid all right.
跟我来
Come with me.
了不起
Impressive.
这是哪里弄来的
Where did you get one of these?
来自一名被捕的帝国指挥官
It was from a captured Imperial commandant
他收藏大量的古董载具
who had a big collection of vintage vehicles.
这架维持原装 修复得无可挑剔
This one is stock. Perfectly restored.
我试飞了一下
I took it out for a test spin.
他们翻修得很到位
They did a nice job on the rebuild.
这比抓那个帝国分子的赏金更值钱
This is worth a lot more than the bounty on that
Imp.
那就当作下回任务的订金吧
Well, let's call it an advance on the next mission.
什么下回任务
What next mission?
科因指挥官
Commander Coin.
我们遗失的权杖王牌
Our missing Ace of Staves.
没人知道他的长相
No one knows what he looks like
多数人认为他死了
and most believe him to be dead.
情报不多 有什么计画
Not a lot to go on. What's the play?
我要你去纳尔赫塔见赫特人
I want you to go to Nal Hutta and meet with the
Hutts.
他们同意指引我们去找他
They've agreed to lead us to him.
他们有什么好处
What's in it for them?
他们的堂侄遭另一个犯罪集团
Their nephew's being held against his will
强行拘留在边境星域
by another crime syndicate on the Outer Rim,
他们要专业高手偷偷救他出来
and they need a professional to get him out quickly
and quietly.
他在哪
Where is he?
他们只愿意亲自告诉你
They'll only tell you in person.
知道名字吗？
You got a name?
他叫赫特人罗塔
His name is Rotta the Hutt.
犯罪头子赫特人贾巴唯一的继承人
The only surviving heir of crime lord Jabba the
Hutt.
见过他吗？
You ever cross his path?
我尽量避免
I tried not to.
那
So
一言为定
do we have a deal?
我只追捕帝国战犯
I only hunt down Imperial war criminals.
已经不为帮派效力了
I don't work for gangsters anymore,
尤其是赫特人
especially the Hutts.
没错 你为我们效力
That's right, you don't. You work for us.
现在 这是我们给你的任务
And right now, this is what we need you to do.
不接 就没报酬给你
You don't want the job, I got nothing for you.
登船
Come aboard.
顺便看看吧
May as well have a look around.
去听听赫特人怎么说
Let's go hear the Hutts out.
这次我还能让你驾驶
I'll even let you fly this time.
我没答应
I didn't say yes.
你也没拒绝
You didn't say no either.
虽然是原装 但状况极佳
She's stock, but she's clean.
嘿 什么都别碰
Hey. Don't touch anything.
绝对不能碰按钮
Never touch the buttons.
表明身分
Identify yourself.
剃刀冠号 请求放行
Razor Crest, requesting clearance.
我受到双胞胎邀请
I'm here by invitation of the Twins.
别紧张
Easy on the sticks.
他们在等我们 应该没事
They're expecting us. We should be fine.
准许通行 你可以前进了
Clearance granted. You are clear to approach.
他们这里火力可不小
They've got a lot of firepower here.
是啊 还雇了机器人家团
Yeah. Looks like they hired the Droid Gotra.
赫特人非常注重安全
The Hutts take security seriously.
赫特人几千年来都是犯罪首脑
The Hutts have been the head of criminal
enterprises for thousands of years.
利用暴力和背叛来掌握控制权
They use violence and treachery to maintain control.
小心
Be careful.
我们虽然是客人 但并不安全
We may be their guests, but we are not safe.
终于见到传说中的曼达洛人
We finally meet the legendary Mandalorian.
很高兴你同意为我们效力
We are so glad you agreed to work for us.
你要发大财了
You will be very rich.
我效力对象不是你们 是新共和国
I don't work for you. I work for the New Republic.
听说你们能指引我们
I'm told you can lead us
找到帝国逃犯科因指挥官
to the Imperial fugitive Commander Coin.
当然 曼多
Of course, Mando.
我知道你们的堂侄罗塔被绑架
I understand your nephew, Rotta, has been kidnapped.
对 我们可怜的堂侄被带走
Yes, our poor nephew has been taken.
他交到了坏朋友
He fell in with a bad crowd.
我们心都碎了
We are heartbroken.
想想你的小不点失踪的感觉
Think of how you would feel if your little one went
missing.
他长什么样子
What does he look like?
有影像吗？
Do you have an image?
有
Ah, yes.
我们唯一的影像是很久以前的
The only image we have is from long ago.
后来他长大了不少
He's had a growth spurt since then.
好 我去救你们堂侄
Okay. I'll rescue your nephew.
他被押在哪里
Where is he being held?
你能在沙卡里卫星找到他
You will find him on the moon of Shakari.
没问题
It shall be done.
我们即将脱离超空间 进入沙卡里星系
We're about to come out of hyperspace in the
Shakari system.
可想而知
To state the obvious, you are operating
你在新共和国管辖区外活动
outside the jurisdiction of the New Republic.
如果失控 我无法呼叫X翼战机支援
If things get messy, I can't call in an X-wing
strike.
我知道程序
I know the drill.
在冲锋陷阵前 先检查盔甲
Before going into harm's way, check your armor
first.
必须很合身 以免滑动
It's gotta fit snug so it doesn't slide,
但不能紧到影响活动
but not so tight that it restricts your movement.
懂吗？
Got it?
感觉如何
How's that feel?
泽布 在这里放我们下去
All right, Zeb, drop us here.
是
Yes?
给这小家伙一份煎肉排
I'll take a flat-meat fry for the little one.
好的 没问题
Got it. Okay, got it, got it.
煎肉排
Flat-meat fry, huh?
对
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
面额真大啊 我不一定找得开
That's quite an impressive denomination. I'm not
sure I've got change for that.
不用找了
You can keep the change.
我刚来这一带
I'm new to these parts.
需要一些情报
I can use some information.
这价码 我知无不言
Yeah, for this price, I'll tell you whatever you
want.
我在找一个赫特人
I'm looking for a Hutt.
别提这名字 别说
Shh. Don't mention that name. Don't say that.
你想害死我们吗？
What, are you trying to get us both killed?
来 钱不用给了 我请客
Here. Keep your credits. Food's on me.
走开 谢谢
Go away. Thank you.
你没来过 快走 没啥好看的
Okay, never happened. Let's go. Nothing to see here.
死曼达洛人 讲那种话
Damn Mandalorian, talking like that.
大庭广众之下 干嘛呀
Just out in the open, he talks like What is this?
不
No, no, no.
不 我不要你的信用币
No, no, no, no. I don't want your credits,
我没给你情报
'cause I didn't give you any information.
他叫罗塔
His name is Rotta.
是吗？
Really?
很好笑吗？
Something funny?
对 大家都认识赫特人罗塔
Yeah, yeah. Everybody Everybody knows Rotta the
Hutt.
那家伙是怪物
That guy's a monster.
罗塔
Rotta Rotta Rotta
我看他不像囚犯
He doesn't seem like a prisoner to me.
罗塔
Rotta
你是来杀我的吗？
Are you here to kill me?
我是来救你的
I'm here to rescue you.
凭什么认为我需要人救
What makes you think I need rescuing?
你堂叔堂姑雇我来找你
Your aunt and uncle hired me to find you.
了解 谢谢你 我不需要人救
Yeah, I see. Well, thank you, but I don't require
rescuing.
明天是我合约中最后一场比赛
Tomorrow's the last match in my contract and after
that,
然后债就还清了
my debt will be paid.
我将恢复自由身
I'll be a free agent.
还债给谁
Paid to who?
他是谁
Who's he?
别盯着他
Don't stare.
没关系 你叫什么名字
It's okay. What's your name?
他不会说话
He doesn't talk.
你得还钱给谁
Who do you have to pay?
我能喂他吗？
Can I feed him?
当然
Sure.
你得还钱给谁
Who do you have to pay?
贾努领主
Lord Janu.
没听过这名字
I don't know the name.
你该知道
You should.
他在所有沙卡里卫星上领导犯罪集团
He runs the Syndicate on all the moons of Shakari.
他将我签入他的旗下
He signed me to his stable.
资助我的住宿和训练
He bankrolled my board and training.
他把你关在笼子里
He keeps you in a cage.
他对我很好
He treats me well.
明天晚上之后 我就自由了
And after tomorrow night, I'll be my own man.
而且他让我当推广人
And with the following he got me as a promoter,
我不但会还清债务 也会很快发财
not only will my debt be paid, but I'll be rich by
the solstice.
古古 过来
Grogu, heel
放心 我不是我父亲
Don't worry, I'm not my father.
你知道父亲是赫特人贾巴
You know how hard it is to be your own man
要当自己有多难吗？
when your father is Jabba the Hutt?
有看到他们为我欢呼吗？
You see them cheering for me out there?
为了我
For me.
我第一次不用活在他的阴影下
It's the first time I'm not living in his shadow.
所以我才上场
That's why I fight in the pits.
他们怕我 但也为我欢呼
They feared him, but they cheer for me.
所以
So, no
我不需要被拯救
I don't need to be rescued.
哪里能找到贾努领主
Where can I find Lord Janu?
谢谢 打烊了
Thank you. Closed for the night.
他在想什么 死曼达洛人
What the hell's he thinking? Damn Mandalorians.
曼达洛人根本不是本地人 到处乱
Mandalorians, they don't even come from here. He's
going around, talking
我想知道在哪能找到贾努领主
I just wanna know where I can find Lord Janu.
别说出来 别说那名字
Don't say that. Do not say that name.
别再说了
Stop saying it.
我建议你冷静一下
I recommend you calm down.
拜托 别杀我
Just, please, please, don't kill me. Don't kill me.
我家有12个小孩 比他还小
I've got I've got 12 little ones at home, smaller
than him.
他们更娇小
It's They're smaller.
对 只是
Yeah, it's just
我付给他保护费
I pay him protection, okay?
我们都有
We all do.
我几乎入不敷出 但至少还活着
I barely make a living, to be honest. But at least
I'm alive.
谁替他收钱
Who collects for him?
不知道 每次的人都不同
I don't know. Different people come in.
有时来这里 有时我送去
Sometimes they come here, sometimes I do a drop
myself.
-哪里 -什么哪里
-What do I know? -Where? Where what?
你送钱去哪里
Where do you do the drops?
有时候我去不同的地方
I don't Some pla Sometimes, I go down to  different
places.
通常 有时我去科文车站底下的盐吧
Usually Sometimes I go to the salt bar under Korvin
Station.
还有别的地方 去
And then there's other places too. You go to
就是 我到处跑
You know. You know, I go around.
我不要 我不要
No, I don't want it. I don't want it.
我没给你情报 只有讲话而已
I didn't give you any information. I was just
talking.
那不是情报
That's not for information.
是付他的帐单
It's to cover his tab.
我找贾努领主
I'm looking for Lord Janu.
你可能搞错了
Maybe you made a mistake.
你可能记错 以为你认识我
Maybe you remember wrong and think you know me.
或许你找错地方了
Maybe you just walked through the wrong door.
我不是来买盐的
Well, I'm not here to buy salt.
盐
Salt?
我们不卖盐
We don't sell salt.
它是配给的
It's on the ration.
你肩上的小可爱多少钱
How much for the shoulder candy?
适合养在笼子里
Would look real pretty in a cage.
我来见贾努领主
I'm here to see Lord Janu.
我不会再说一次
I won't repeat myself again.
你今天的表现没白费
It seems you've earned your salt today.
我是贾努
I'm Janu.
到后面来挑颗水晶盐
Come to the back and pick out a crystal.
哈斯布雷 叫他们清理一下
Hogsbreth, have the boys clean up.
宠物一只都不能少
Make sure I don't lose any pets.
来
Here.
挑一颗
Choose one.
盐在我老家没有价值
Salt is of no value to me where I'm from.
在这里价值不菲
But here it's worth a small fortune,
因为是由政治人物配给的
because it's rationed by the politicians.
所以很稀有
Which makes it rare.
你也一样 曼达洛人
As are you, Mandalorian.
考虑过来斗技坑比赛吗？
Have you ever considered fighting in the pits?
我尽量避免暴力
I try to avoid violence.
那当然
'Course you do.
我也是
I do as well.
如果不买盐 什么风把你吹来
So what brings you to this establishment if you're
not in the market for salt?
我想买断你旗下一名斗士的合约
I wanna buy out the contract on a fighter from your
stable.
也许你能考虑加入我旗下
Perhaps you would consider joining my stable
instead?
这在我老家能买不少盐
This buys a lot of salt where I'm from.
用来交换赫特人罗塔的格斗合约
I am offering you this in exchange for the fighting
contract on Rotta the Hutt.
再高的价钱也买不到他最后一战
My dear boy, there's no price high enough to buy
him out of his last fights.
我培训他好多周期了
I've been grooming that little prince for many
cycles,
准备迎接明天的比赛
setting him up for tomorrow's match.
收下信用币
Take the credits.
反正是他为你打的最后一战
It's his last fight for you anyway.
他毕生最后一战
It's his last fight ever.
我搜集来自银河系各地的致命动物
I've collected the most deadly creatures from
across the galaxy.
他要上场比异兽棋
He's fighting a Dejarik match?
对
Yes.
他明天就会死
He will die tomorrow.
只有少数几人知道
And a select few know it.
我送你以下的赠礼
Here's my gift to you:
用这些信用币 下注那个赫特人会死
take those credits, bet it all on the death of the
Hutt.
我只要你考虑在我的斗技坑出赛
In exchange, all I ask is that you consider
fighting in my pit.
沙卡里人愿不计代价目睹奇观
The people of Shakari would pay any price to see
the rarest of sights,
传奇曼达洛战士参加血腥运动
one of the legendary Mandalorian warriors engaging
in blood sport.
这应该能弥补我们的小误会
This should more than cover our little
misunderstanding out there.
我只要求你考虑我的提议
All I ask is that you consider my offer.
我们俩都能发大财
Could make us both very rich.
看来我们只能来硬的了
Looks like we're gonna have to do this the hard way.
什么
What?
贾努打算杀了你
Janu's planning on killing you.
我救你出去
I'm here to get you out.
明天是最后一场 打赢就自由了
Tomorrow's my last fight. I'll be free after I win.
胜负已定 那是异兽棋比赛
The fix is in. It's a Dejarik match.
他会不断派出对手 直到你死
He will keep throwing opponents at you until you
die.
我何必相信你
Why should I believe you?
我堂叔堂姑派你来 他们要我死
You were sent by my aunt and uncle who want me dead.
他们要你回去
They want you back.
你害他们丢脸
You're embarrassing them.
双胞胎要我死
The Twins want me dead
因为王位继承人是我 不是他们
because I'm heir to the throne, not them.
但我不要王位
But I don't want it.
我根本不想和我父亲一样
I don't wanna be anything like my father.
刚开始参赛 观众都嘘我
When I first started fighting, the people all booed
me.
他们想看我死
They wanted to see me die
因为我是赫特人贾巴的儿子
because I'm the son of Jabba the Hutt.
后来我赢得冠军
Then I won and became a champion
他们才慢慢开始欢呼
and they slowly began to cheer.
他们明白我不是我父亲
They realized I'm not my father.
我是我自己
I'm my own man,
我不怕捍卫自己
and I'm not afraid to fight for what I have.
努力争取 向大家证明自己
To earn it. To prove myself to everyone.
孩子 格斗不是运动
Kid, fighting's not a sport.
它是最后的手段
It's a last resort.
跟我来 以免无法收拾
Now come with me before things get ugly.
警卫 他回来了
Guards, he's back
出去
Get out. Get out
罗塔
Rotta Rotta Rotta
Rotta
我不想跟你打
I don't want to fight you.
那你今天有得受了
Then you're in for a long day
好啊
Yes
我不会杀你
I'm not going to kill you.
我是来救你的
I'm here to rescue you.
杀
Kill Kill Kill Kill
Kill Kill Kill
我认输
I yield.
赫特人罗塔获胜
Rotta the Hutt has won.
现在你得放他自由
Now you owe him his freedom.
赫特人罗塔获胜
Rotta the Hutt has won.
现在他自由了
Now he is free
可以死了
to die
我们合作才有机会
Our only chance is to work together.
注意那个小的
Watch out for the little one.
好 让我来
Yeah, I got this.
我们该走了
We should go now.
快走
Now
没事吧
Are you good?
放心 老弟 我们离开这里
Don't worry, buddy. We're getting out of here.
你说得对 胜负已定
You were right. The fix was in.
我带你离开
Let's get you out of here.
我去找交通工具
I'm gonna find us a ride.
抱歉 曼多
Sorry, Mando.
我不能回去
I can't go back.
泽布 有人想逃
Zeb, I got a runner.
好啦 被你逮到了
Okay, you got me.
我也是情有可原
Can't blame a guy for trying.
我们即将跳到超空间
We're about to jump to hyperspace.
你要带我去哪
Where are you bringing me?
把你绑着不安全
It's not safe to keep you chained up.
如果帮你解开
If I unlock you,
你保证不动歪脑筋吗？
can we agree to no funny stuff?
你要带我去纳尔赫塔吗？
Are you bringing me to Nal Hutta?
这艘船老了 有时会摇晃
This is an old ship. Sometimes things get a little
bouncy.
我堂叔堂姑很怕我爸
My aunt and uncle were scared of my father.
他们一直对我很差
They've always been cruel to me.
现在他们掌控他的犯罪帝国 得干掉我
Now that they control his criminal empire, they
need me eliminated.
带我去给他们 我就死定了
You bring me to them, I'm a dead man.
你又不确定
You don't know that.
如果放我走 我再也不会出现
If you let me go, you'll never hear from me again.
银河系很大
It's a big galaxy.
我能消失
I can disappear.
抱歉 孩子
Sorry, kid.
我受雇来执行任务
I was hired to do a job.
你晚上竟然睡得着
I don't know how you sleep at night,
为那些禽兽效力
working for those monsters.
我不是为他们效力
I don't work for them,
我为新共和国效力
I work for the New Republic.
雇用我的是他们 不是双胞胎
They hired me, not the Twins.
回去后 他们会给我科因指挥官的下落
When I bring you back, they're giving me the
whereabouts of Commander Coin,
在边境星域活动的前帝国高官
a high-ranking ex-Imperial operating on the Outer
Rim.
是贾努
It's Janu.
你在找的人是贾努
The man you're looking for is Janu.
贾努·科因领主
Lord Janu Coin.
赫特人会把他交给你 他是前帝国官员
That's who the Hutts are gonna give you. He's ex-
Imperial.
不可能 不然双胞胎会告诉我
That can't be. The Twins would've told me.
我看见风暴兵
I saw stormtroopers.
他曾带我去他家庆祝大胜利
He brought me to his estate once to celebrate a big
win
到处都有风暴兵
and there were stormtroopers everywhere.
如果不相信我 现在不抓他
If you don't believe me and you don't get him now,
以后就没机会了
you won't get another shot.
其实可能太迟了
In fact, it might already be too late.
好离奇的故事
That's quite a story.
我干嘛相信你
Why should I believe you?
你是赏金猎人
You're a bounty hunter,
有人说谎你看得出来
you know when someone's lying.
我是在说谎
Am I lying
还是在说实话
or am I telling the truth?
就是那里
That's it.
那是贾努·科因的宅邸
That's Janu Coin's compound.
大块头说的可能是实话
Could be big boy's telling the truth.
那里全是风暴兵
The place is lousy with stormtroopers.
你在里面看到几个
How many did you see when you were in there?
很多
A lot.
如果想进去 你需要大量支援
You're gonna need a lot of backup if you're
actually thinking of going in.
嗯哼
Uh-huh.
通知沙卡里暗面的
Get word to all our foot soldiers
所有步兵
on the dark side of Shakari.
监视星际港与所有货运航线
I want eyes on the starport and all the freight
lanes.
向市长施压
Lean on the mayor.
找到他们之前不准起降
Nothing takes off or lands until we find them.
召集我的个人保全部队
Muster my personal security forces.
我们全副武装上街
We're going to hit the streets in full armor.
对付曼达洛人 我不想冒险
I don't want to take any chances when it comes to
The Mandalorian.
我听过那些怪物的不少事迹
I've heard many things about those monsters.
全是真的
It's all true.
帝国指挥官贾努·科因
Imperial Commander Janu Coin,
我代表新共和国来将你绳之以法
I'm here on behalf of the New Republic to bring you
to justice.
我们不在你的管辖范围内
I'm afraid we're outside of your jurisdiction.
杀了他
Take him
火力全开 -快点
-Set blasters on full. -Hurry
我可以热着带你回去
I can bring you in warm
也可以凉着带你回去
or I can bring you in cold.
古古
Grogu.
罗塔
Rotta.
罗塔 请回答
Rotta, come in.
有人听见了吗？
Does anyone read me?
-我醒了 -我需要你发动引擎
-I'm up. I'm up. -I need you to fire up the drives.
-发动引擎 有人追来了 -收到
-Fire up the drives. We have company. -Received.
我不会驾船 你会吗？
I don't know how to fly. Do you know how to fly?
我们都不会开 我连驾驶舱都进不去
Neither of us know how to fly, and I can't even fit
in the cockpit.
古古 你到控制台去
Grogu, I need you to go to the control panel.
记得我教你不准碰的按钮吗？
Remember the buttons I told you never to touch?
你现在要碰它们了
I'm gonna need you to touch them.
找点火继电器断路开关
Look for the ignition relay cutoff.
在燃料差压读数旁
It's next to the fuel differential readout,
它就在泵压计和
which is between the pump compression gauge
主备用量指示——
and the primary reserve indic
别碰导弹电池开关
No. Don't touch the missile battery switch.
所以上面才有防护罩
That's why there's a safety guard on it.
有看到燃料读数显示器吗？
Do you see the fuel readout display?
记得我给你看过吗？
Remember I showed you that one?
在手动控制面校准装置的另一——
It's on the other side of the manual control
surface calibration un
你把他搞糊涂了
I don't think he knows what he's doing.
下来
Get out.
快跑 他们也会射杀你
Get going. They're shooting at you too.
干得好 系好安全带
Good job, buddy. Strap in.
我喜欢这小子
I like this kid.
快啊
Come on. Come on.
带我们离开大气层 跳
Get us out of atmosphere and jump
上来 你得绕过排气节流阀
Get up here. I need you to bypass the exhaust
restrictors.
这艘破船会害死我们
This old junker's gonna get us killed.
我需要更多动力
I need more power.
停用安全控制面板 我好手动解除限制器
Disable the safety panel so I can override the
limiter.
怎么做 我是飞行员 不是技工
How? I'm a pilot, not a meknek.
拆掉主控板
Just rip out the whole brain board.
上面都还好吗？
Everything okay up there?
好到不行
Perfect.
叫你系安全带 随时都要系好
I told you to strap in. Always wear your seat belt.
飞稳一点
Take it easy up there
漂亮
There we go.
看起来不像赫特人
That doesn't look like a Hutt.
这是帝国指挥官贾努·科因
This is Imperial Commander Janu Coin.
他有很多情报 准备大方分享
He's full of information and ready to sing like a
Yuzzum.
是不是 科因
Isn't that right, Coin?
如果接受讯问 我要求律师在场
I demand an attorney be present if I'm to be
questioned.
看吧
You see?
他有好多秘密
He's full of secrets.
你该带罗塔回来的
You were supposed to bring back Rotta.
我们跟双胞胎讲好了
We had an arrangement with the Twins.
这是你的权杖王牌
This is your Ace of Staves.
这是他们会指引你去找的人
This is who they were going to lead you to.
然后向他通风报信
And then tip him off,
出卖你 两头赚
sell you out and collect credits from both sides.
带走
Take him away.
情报局经营与赫特人的关系
Intelligence has been cultivating a relationship
with the Hutts
很长一段时间
for a very long time,
你却和他们作对
and you crossed them.
双胞胎不会善罢甘休
The Twins can hold a grudge.
我做了决定
I made a call.
带大礼来给你
I got you the big prize.
双胞胎可以去死了
The Twins can rot in hell.
你领不到他们找堂侄的大笔赏金了
Well, you missed out on them paying you a big
bounty for their nephew.
那就算了
So be it.
我可以问问高层能否支付逮捕科因的费用
Well, I'll see if I can hit up Command for a fee
for the capture of Coin.
别麻烦了 算我的
Don't worry about it. It's on me.
这次搞得很累
This one got messy.
我要休息一下
I'm taking a break.
我了解
I understand.
曼多
Mando.
干得好
Good job.
我们要拿掉限流板
We're gonna pull the restrictor plates.
第一个应该就在回流管后面
The first one should be just past the return line.
对
That's it.
应该还有三个
There should be three more.
好
Okay, okay. Okey-doke.
Okay, okay.
谢谢你们来
Thanks for coming.
别客气
No problem.
我想做些性能改装
I'm looking to make some performance modifications.
我得移除不必要的重量
I need to cut out dead weight for speed.
拿掉拖慢速度的东西
Pull out anything that doesn't make her go.
嘿
Hey Hey. Hey.
-别碰我 -过来
-No, don't touch me -Heel.
-好可怕的宝宝 -坏宝宝
-The horrible baby. -The bad baby.
别动
Stay.
我清洗过油管 想移除所有限流器
I purged the fuel lines. I wanna remove all the
restrictors
和疏通排气管
and unplug the exhaust.
-知道了 -没问题 交给我
-Got it. Yeah, yeah. -No problem. Yeah. I got it.
-没问题 -好的
-No problem. -Yeah. Okey-doke.
你想去帮他们吗？
You wanna go help them?
你答应不会乱来
Do you promise to play nice?
好 去吧
All right. Go.
别担心他
Don't worry about him.
小家伙没事的
Little guy's gonna be okay.
抱歉 我在你厨房找到这个
Sorry, I found these in your kitchen.
我在他这年纪孤单一人
I was alone when I was his age.
必须照顾自己
I had to fend for myself.
幸好他有你
He's lucky he has you.
你长大后挺好的
Well, you didn't turn out half bad.
生活不如意 但我们尽力而为
Life's messy, but we do the best we can.
听着 我找了个军火商带你离开这星系
Listen, I called a gunrunner who agreed to take you
out of the system.
我们都知道双胞胎会找你
We both know the Twins will be looking for you,
你最好继续移动
so you best keep moving.
谢谢你 曼多
Thank you, Mando.
这笔交易很公平
It was a fair trade.
记得低调点
Make sure you lay low.
我不想又在名单上看到你
I don't wanna see your name on my list again.
我答应你
You have my word.
保重了 小家伙
All right, you take care of yourself, little guy.
也要盯好你的老爸 好吗？
And keep an eye on your old man, too, all right?
给你
Here you go.
帮我保管
Hang on to these for me.
剩下的留着晚餐后吃
Let's save the rest of these for after dinner.
起来
Wake up.
什么
What?
-起来 外面有人 -怎么了
-Wake up. There's someone out there. -What's going
on?
-早上了吗？ -安静
-I'll be awake in the morning. -Quiet.
到地板底下
Get under the floor.
等着 我打信号就出去
Wait here. If I signal, get out.
救命 它咬住我了
Help It got me It got me
警部
Keibu.
快走
有抓到曼达洛人吗？
Did you get the Mandalorian?
非常好 带他来纳尔赫塔
Very good. Bring him to Nal Hutta.
救我 救命
Help me Help
放开他
Let him go.
嘿 你饿了吗？
Hey, you hungry?
要吃点心吗？
You want a treat?
给你
Here you go.
好乖
Good girl.
快过来
Come on. Come on
噢哦
Uh-oh.
谁雇用你的
Who hired you?
赫特人吗？
Was it the Hutts?
如果是赫特人
Well, if it was the Hutts,
我一定会让他们付你合理报酬
I'd make sure they're paying you what you're worth.
但我猜久藏人够聪明 会先拿钱
But I'm guessing a Kyuzo is smart enough to get
their money up-front
纳尔赫塔
Nal Hutta.
赫特人在那里 我不喜欢
The Hutts are there. I don't like it.
哇 我来了
Oh Wow Oh, I'm coming.
孩子 别害怕 没事
-Kid, don't be scared. -Don't be scared. It's okay,
yeah.
来 走吧
Come on, let's go.
哈啰 是我 你们来了
Hello It's me, it's me You're here.
你们来找我 找到我了
You came for me You found me
我们以为你死了
Oh, we thought you were dead.
曼达洛人救了我
Mandalorian, he saved me.
大个子 他在里面
Big guy. He's inside there.
我们得去找他 带他回家
Yeah, we got to go and find him and bring him home
for the baby.
那条大狗 大狗
The big thing. The big dog. The big dog. The big
它把我叼起来
Oh, oh. It picked me up
曼多在里面 王宫里
Mando is in there. In the palace.
来 上来
Come on. Up, up, up, up.
加油 你可以的
Come on, baby. You can do it.
好大的涵管
Big pipe, huh?
神准 宝贝
Good shot, baby.
付钱给猎人
Pay the hunter.
你破坏我们的协议
You broke our agreement.
现在你得付出代价
Now you must pay.
把他的头盔拿给我
Bring me his helmet.
曼达洛钢
Mandalorian steel.
在黑市上奇货可居
Priceless on the black market.
但比不过知道
But worth even more is knowing
我们永远羞辱了你
we have shamed you forever.
我们知道曼达洛信条
We know the Mandalorian Creed.
让敌人看见你的脸 你会遭流放
You will be outcast for letting an enemy see your
face.
你们死了就不会
Not if you all die.
看你坚强的精神崩溃
It will bring us ecstasy
会带给我们无上的喜乐
to watch your strong spirit break.
禽兽
Monsters.
这是你造成的
You did this to him.
罗塔原本会平静死去
Rotta would have died painlessly,
但你背叛我们
but you betrayed us.
现在他会痛苦好几个世纪
Now he will suffer for centuries.
因为赫特人能活几百年
You see, Hutts live for hundreds of years.
就像你的绿色小朋友一样
Just like your small, green child.
有一天你会死
One day you will die,
古古就没有你来保护他
and Grogu will be without you to protect him.
到时就换他受苦
And then, it will be his turn to suffer.
我们被你逗乐了
You have entertained us.
这是你的奖赏
Here is your reward.
噢哦 往哪边
Uh-oh. Which way?
就算你赢 也会中毒而死
Even if you win, you will die from the poison.
该死
Dank farrik.
出去 快走
Get out Go
快走 快点
Come on, go Go, go
噢耶 -哇
-Oh, yeah -Wow
等等
Wait. Wait.
还好吗？
You okay?
-你们怎么来的 -我们有船
-How did you get here? -We got a ship.
那边 快走
That way. Let's go
派出机器人 释出阿玛尼人
Send the droids Release the Amani
别让他跑了
Don't let him escape
这边
This way. This way, yeah.
-这边 -下面
This way
上去 上去
Up, up, up, up, going up
我不要下去 不要
I don't want to fall. I don't want to.
快走
Go
好 我们走
Yeah. Okay, okay. Yeah. Let's go.
去吧 孩子 我挤不进去的
Go, kid. I can't fit in that thing,
你必须离开
but you have to leave.
放心
Don't worry.
我随后就来
I'll be right behind you.
快走 我来拖延他们
Go now. I'll hold them off.
我们会回来找你 曼多
We'll come back for you, Mando.
来啊 宝贝
Come on, baby.
放心 我们会回来的
Don't worry. We'll be back.
快点
Yeah, let's go. Let's go.
快来 宝贝
Come on, baby.
再见 孩子
Goodbye, kid.
未侦测到生命迹象
No life force detected.
我想是你偷走我的鱼
Methinks you are the one who stole my fish.
我猜你不是这边的人
I'm guessing you're not from around here.
你这种小不点应该更小心
A morsel like you should be more careful.
看来你处于纳尔赫塔食物链底层
You look to be the bottom of the Nal Hutta food
chain.
我很惊讶你还没上赫特人的餐桌
I'm surprised you haven't found your way to the
Hutts' supper table.
听过赫特人吧
You've heard of the Hutts, have you?
你害怕吗？
Are you scared?
应该的
You should be.
他们有机会就会整个吞掉你
They would swallow you whole given half a chance.
去躲起来
Make yourself scarce.
噢哦
Uh-huh.
嘿
Hey.
别想碰我的鱼
Get away from my fish.
警部
Keibu.
那个猎人说你有同伴
The hunter says you have a partner.
你们俩逃出双胞胎的魔爪
Says you two escaped the Twins.
了不起
Well, that's impressive.
他说你的同伴受重伤
Says your partner's hurt real bad.
被龙蛇咬 中毒了
Bit by a dragonsnake. Poisoned.
你喂这个给他吃
I want you to feed this to him.
你该知道 可能来不及了
Now, you should know, this might be too little, too
late,
他很可能不会醒来
and there's a good chance he doesn't wake up.
反正 现在只能让他舒服点
Either way, best thing you can do right now is make
him comfortable.
人生终须一别
There comes a time where we all have to say goodbye.
祝你好运 小旅人
I wish you luck, small traveler.
孩子
Hey, kiddo.
老者保护幼者 幼者保护老者
The old protect the young, and then the young
protect the old.
我辈之道
This is the Way.
我们如何离开这星球
Now how do we get off this planet?
那是带走罗塔的军火商
That's the gunrunner that was carrying Rotta.
孩子 我看我们有两个选择
Well, kid, the way I see it we got two choices.
我们能靠这艘船离开
We can use this ship. Get off world.
或许能争取点时间 一点平静
That might buy us some time. A little bit of peace.
但赫特人会不断来找我们
But the Hutts will keep coming for us.
就像他们来找罗塔一样
Just like they came for Rotta.
所以要逃吗？
So, do we run?
还是要反抗
Or do we fight?
击退入侵者
Repel the intruders
收到
Roger, roger
保护王宫
Protect the palace
是
Affirmative.
听我的指示
Follow my lead.
发射
Fire
快啊
Come on. Come on.
跟我来
On me.
后退
Fall back
等等 我们知道的不少
Wait We know much.
去救罗塔
Go help Rotta.
你们看过我的脸
You saw my face.
住手
Stop
死期到了
Now it's time to die.
离他远一点
Leave him alone
你没有贾巴来保护你
You don't have Jabba to protect you.
我不是小孩子了
I'm not little anymore
住手 你会害死我们
Stop You'll kill us all
救救我们 赏金猎人
Save us, bounty hunter Keibu.
救救我们
Save us
时间不多 我们得快离开
We don't have much time. We have to get out of here.
有别的出路吗？
Is there another way out?
-应该是那边 -快走 快走
-I think it's that way. -Go. Go
发现目标
Target sighted.
-喂 -曼多 我们回来了
-Hello? -Mando We came back.
-什么 -我们回来了
-What? -We came back.
我们就说会回来
We told you we would.
阿德尔菲中队 进入大气层
Adelphi Squadron, entering atmosphere.
-你状况如何 曼多 -我们遭受攻击
-What's your status, Mando? -We're under attack.
他们数量太多了
There are too many.
快对我的位置火力全开
Fire everything you have at my location.
-你的位置 -对 我的位置
-Your location? -Yes, my location.
我不能下这种命令
I can't give that order.
放心
Don't worry
等你下令我们就离开了
we'll be out of here by the time you do.
祝你好运
Good luck.
蓝色中队长呼叫中队
Blue Leader to squadron,
成防御队形 准备交战
assume defensive formation, prepare to engage.
武器待命
All weapons hot.
收到
Copy that.
敌方战斗机靠近
Enemy fighters approaching.
他们来了
Here they come.
正前方有涡轮雷射
Turbolasers, up ahead.
知道了
Got it.
我后面有一架
I've got one on my tail.
看我的
I got you.
好耶
-Yippee Yay
摧毁发射管
Taking out the launch tubes.
蓝色中队长呼叫红色干扰机 标记并锁定
Blue Leader to Red Jammer, mark it and lock it in.
锁定目标
Locking in target.
这是死路
It's a dead end.
我们困住了
We're trapped.
让开
Stand back.
我们快靠近了
We're closing fast.
重复 快靠近了
Repeat, we're closing fast.
你最好离开 曼多
You better be out of there, Mando.
跳
Jump.
这里好高啊
That's a long way down.
接近目标
Closing on target.
-非跳不可 -壕沟没那么深
-Gotta jump. -Moat's not that deep.
是轰炸机 跳
It's a bomber. Jump.
轰了这座丛林沼泽
Let's light up this swamp.
有人看见曼多吗？
Anybody got eyes on Mando?
他们在那里
There they are.
泽布 该收垃圾了
Zeb, go collect the trash.
我受够了这些营救行动
I'm getting a little tired of these hot extractions.
怎么这么久才来
What took you so long?
上来吧
Hop in.
我们回家吧
Let's head home.
上校
Colonel.
乱来
Messy.
真是太乱来了
Very messy.
为什么来救我 这不在任务范围内吧
Why'd you come for me? That wasn't part of the
mission.
你说得对 科因全都招了
You were right. Coin told us everything.
双胞胎一直在耍我们
The Twins were playing us.
给帝国提供情报
Feeding information to the Empire all along.
他们站队了 站的不是我们
They picked a side. It wasn't ours.
而且 我们不会抛弃自己人
Besides, we don't leave our own behind.
我是独立承包商
I'm an independent contractor.
是 曼多 你当然是
Sure, Mando. Sure you are.
我能载你去哪里吗？
Can I give you a ride somewhere?
我在想我能留下来
Actually, I was thinking I could stay here.
或许为新共和国工作
Maybe work for the New Republic.
别误会 但我觉得你不适合
Don't take this the wrong way, but I'm not sure you
would fit in.
其实 我有制服适合他穿
You know I might have a uniform that would fit him.
走吧 我请你喝一杯
Come on, let me buy you a drink.
谢谢你曼多 我欠你一次
Thank you, Mando. I owe you big time.
我只是尽忠职守
Just doing my job.
好好看着他
And keep an eye on him.
你有个好爸爸
Your dad's one of the good ones.
走吧 大个子
Come on, big guy.
小心走 第一轮我请客
Watch your step. First round's on me.
孩子 上来
Hey, kid. Come up here.
轮到你了
Your turn.
动手吧
Go ahead.
曼达洛人与古古